<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Minh Vu Nguyen</title>
        <link>https://minhvu1512.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Minh Vu Nguyen</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 02:45:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://minhvu1512.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
            <link>https://minhvu1512.github.io/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://minhvu1512.github.io/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;move-static-content-to-static&#34;&gt;Move static content to &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; will be copied as-is to the &lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; output. Hugo keeps all static content under &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;. You should therefore move it all there.
With Jekyll, something that looked like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/
    ▾ images/
        logo.png
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;should become&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/
    ▾ static/
        ▾ images/
            logo.png
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt;) to be moved to &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="move-static-content-to-static">Move static content to <code>static</code></h2>
<p>Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with <code>_</code> will be copied as-is to the <code>_site</code> output. Hugo keeps all static content under <code>static</code>. You should therefore move it all there.
With Jekyll, something that looked like</p>
<pre><code>▾ &lt;root&gt;/
    ▾ images/
        logo.png
</code></pre>
<p>should become</p>
<pre><code>▾ &lt;root&gt;/
    ▾ static/
        ▾ images/
            logo.png
</code></pre>
<p>Additionally, you&rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as <code>CNAME</code>) to be moved to <code>static</code>.</p>
<h2 id="create-your-hugo-configuration-file">Create your Hugo configuration file</h2>
<p>Hugo can read your configuration as JSON, YAML or TOML. Hugo supports parameters custom configuration too. Refer to the <a href="/overview/configuration/">Hugo configuration documentation</a> for details.</p>
<h2 id="set-your-configuration-publish-folder-to-_site">Set your configuration publish folder to <code>_site</code></h2>
<p>The default is for Jekyll to publish to <code>_site</code> and for Hugo to publish to <code>public</code>. If, like me, you have <a href="http://blog.blindgaenger.net/generate_github_pages_in_a_submodule.html"><code>_site</code> mapped to a git submodule on the <code>gh-pages</code> branch</a>, you&rsquo;ll want to do one of two alternatives:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Change your submodule to point to map <code>gh-pages</code> to public instead of <code>_site</code> (recommended).</p>
<pre><code> git submodule deinit _site
 git rm _site
 git submodule add -b gh-pages git@github.com:your-username/your-repo.git public
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>
<p>Or, change the Hugo configuration to use <code>_site</code> instead of <code>public</code>.</p>
<pre><code> {
     ..
     &quot;publishdir&quot;: &quot;_site&quot;,
     ..
 }
</code></pre>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="convert-jekyll-templates-to-hugo-templates">Convert Jekyll templates to Hugo templates</h2>
<p>That&rsquo;s the bulk of the work right here. The documentation is your friend. You should refer to <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/templates/">Jekyll&rsquo;s template documentation</a> if you need to refresh your memory on how you built your blog and <a href="/layout/templates/">Hugo&rsquo;s template</a> to learn Hugo&rsquo;s way.</p>
<p>As a single reference data point, converting my templates for <a href="http://heyitsalex.net/">heyitsalex.net</a> took me no more than a few hours.</p>
<h2 id="convert-jekyll-plugins-to-hugo-shortcodes">Convert Jekyll plugins to Hugo shortcodes</h2>
<p>Jekyll has <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/plugins/">plugins</a>; Hugo has <a href="/doc/shortcodes/">shortcodes</a>. It&rsquo;s fairly trivial to do a port.</p>
<h3 id="implementation">Implementation</h3>
<p>As an example, I was using a custom <a href="https://github.com/alexandre-normand/alexandre-normand/blob/74bb12036a71334fdb7dba84e073382fc06908ec/_plugins/image_tag.rb"><code>image_tag</code></a> plugin to generate figures with caption when running Jekyll. As I read about shortcodes, I found Hugo had a nice built-in shortcode that does exactly the same thing.</p>
<p>Jekyll&rsquo;s plugin:</p>
<pre><code>module Jekyll
  class ImageTag &lt; Liquid::Tag
    @url = nil
    @caption = nil
    @class = nil
    @link = nil
    // Patterns
    IMAGE_URL_WITH_CLASS_AND_CAPTION =
    IMAGE_URL_WITH_CLASS_AND_CAPTION_AND_LINK = /(\w+)(\s+)((https?:\/\/|\/)(\S+))(\s+)&quot;(.*?)&quot;(\s+)-&gt;((https?:\/\/|\/)(\S+))(\s*)/i
    IMAGE_URL_WITH_CAPTION = /((https?:\/\/|\/)(\S+))(\s+)&quot;(.*?)&quot;/i
    IMAGE_URL_WITH_CLASS = /(\w+)(\s+)((https?:\/\/|\/)(\S+))/i
    IMAGE_URL = /((https?:\/\/|\/)(\S+))/i
    def initialize(tag_name, markup, tokens)
      super
      if markup =~ IMAGE_URL_WITH_CLASS_AND_CAPTION_AND_LINK
        @class   = $1
        @url     = $3
        @caption = $7
        @link = $9
      elsif markup =~ IMAGE_URL_WITH_CLASS_AND_CAPTION
        @class   = $1
        @url     = $3
        @caption = $7
      elsif markup =~ IMAGE_URL_WITH_CAPTION
        @url     = $1
        @caption = $5
      elsif markup =~ IMAGE_URL_WITH_CLASS
        @class = $1
        @url   = $3
      elsif markup =~ IMAGE_URL
        @url = $1
      end
    end
    def render(context)
      if @class
        source = &quot;&lt;figure class='#{@class}'&gt;&quot;
      else
        source = &quot;&lt;figure&gt;&quot;
      end
      if @link
        source += &quot;&lt;a href=\&quot;#{@link}\&quot;&gt;&quot;
      end
      source += &quot;&lt;img src=\&quot;#{@url}\&quot;&gt;&quot;
      if @link
        source += &quot;&lt;/a&gt;&quot;
      end
      source += &quot;&lt;figcaption&gt;#{@caption}&lt;/figcaption&gt;&quot; if @caption
      source += &quot;&lt;/figure&gt;&quot;
      source
    end
  end
end
Liquid::Template.register_tag('image', Jekyll::ImageTag)
</code></pre>
<p>is written as this Hugo shortcode:</p>
<pre><code>&lt;!-- image --&gt;
&lt;figure {{ with .Get &quot;class&quot; }}class=&quot;{{.}}&quot;{{ end }}&gt;
    {{ with .Get &quot;link&quot;}}&lt;a href=&quot;{{.}}&quot;&gt;{{ end }}
        &lt;img src=&quot;{{ .Get &quot;src&quot; }}&quot; {{ if or (.Get &quot;alt&quot;) (.Get &quot;caption&quot;) }}alt=&quot;{{ with .Get &quot;alt&quot;}}{{.}}{{else}}{{ .Get &quot;caption&quot; }}{{ end }}&quot;{{ end }} /&gt;
    {{ if .Get &quot;link&quot;}}&lt;/a&gt;{{ end }}
    {{ if or (or (.Get &quot;title&quot;) (.Get &quot;caption&quot;)) (.Get &quot;attr&quot;)}}
    &lt;figcaption&gt;{{ if isset .Params &quot;title&quot; }}
        {{ .Get &quot;title&quot; }}{{ end }}
        {{ if or (.Get &quot;caption&quot;) (.Get &quot;attr&quot;)}}&lt;p&gt;
        {{ .Get &quot;caption&quot; }}
        {{ with .Get &quot;attrlink&quot;}}&lt;a href=&quot;{{.}}&quot;&gt; {{ end }}
            {{ .Get &quot;attr&quot; }}
        {{ if .Get &quot;attrlink&quot;}}&lt;/a&gt; {{ end }}
        &lt;/p&gt; {{ end }}
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    {{ end }}
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;!-- image --&gt;
</code></pre>
<h3 id="usage">Usage</h3>
<p>I simply changed:</p>
<pre><code>{% image full http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4136/4829260124_57712e570a_o_d.jpg &quot;One of my favorite touristy-type photos. I secretly waited for the good light while we were &quot;having fun&quot; and took this. Only regret: a stupid pole in the top-left corner of the frame I had to clumsily get rid of at post-processing.&quot; -&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexnormand/4829260124/in/set-72157624547713078/ %}
</code></pre>
<p>to this (this example uses a slightly extended version named <code>fig</code>, different than the built-in <code>figure</code>):</p>
<pre><code>{{% fig class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4136/4829260124_57712e570a_o_d.jpg&quot; title=&quot;One of my favorite touristy-type photos. I secretly waited for the good light while we were having fun and took this. Only regret: a stupid pole in the top-left corner of the frame I had to clumsily get rid of at post-processing.&quot; link=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexnormand/4829260124/in/set-72157624547713078/&quot; %}}
</code></pre>
<p>As a bonus, the shortcode named parameters are, arguably, more readable.</p>
<h2 id="finishing-touches">Finishing touches</h2>
<h3 id="fix-content">Fix content</h3>
<p>Depending on the amount of customization that was done with each post with Jekyll, this step will require more or less effort. There are no hard and fast rules here except that <code>hugo server --watch</code> is your friend. Test your changes and fix errors as needed.</p>
<h3 id="clean-up">Clean up</h3>
<p>You&rsquo;ll want to remove the Jekyll configuration at this point. If you have anything else that isn&rsquo;t used, delete it.</p>
<h2 id="a-practical-example-in-a-diff">A practical example in a diff</h2>
<p><a href="http://heyitsalex.net/">Hey, it&rsquo;s Alex</a> was migrated in less than a <em>father-with-kids day</em> from Jekyll to Hugo. You can see all the changes (and screw-ups) by looking at this <a href="https://github.com/alexandre-normand/alexandre-normand/compare/869d69435bd2665c3fbf5b5c78d4c22759d7613a...b7f6605b1265e83b4b81495423294208cc74d610">diff</a>.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>2024 Recap</title>
            <link>https://minhvu1512.github.io/posts/2024_recap/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 02:45:34 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://minhvu1512.github.io/posts/2024_recap/</guid>
            <description>&lt;head&gt;
   &lt;title&gt;2024 Recap&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://minhvu1512.github.io/images/2024_recap/Bana.JPG&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img 
      src=&#34;https://minhvu1512.github.io/images/2024_recap/Bana.JPG&#34; 
      alt=&#34;Bana cabel cars&#34;
    &gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bana cabel cars&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
Overall, 2024 thăng trầm cũng nhiều nhưng cũng nhờ vậy tui đã chính chắn hơn và cũng đã tìm được mục tiêu trong cuộc sống. Để tổng kết lại năm vừa rồi thì post này sẽ như một cái archive lưu trữ những sự kiện chính trong năm.
&lt;h4 id=&#34;142-192-hội-dn-dn-gặp-mặt-lần-đầu&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;14/2-19/2: Hội DN-DN gặp mặt lần đầu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://minhvu1512.github.io/images/2024_recap/Beachshoes.JPG&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img 
      src=&#34;https://minhvu1512.github.io/images/2024_recap/Beachshoes.JPG&#34; 
      alt=&#34;Beachshoes&#34;
    &gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Random pic of our shoes at Mỹ Khê beach&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<head>
   <title>2024 Recap</title>
</head>
<figure>
  <a href="https://minhvu1512.github.io/images/2024_recap/Bana.JPG">
    <img 
      src="/images/2024_recap/Bana.JPG" 
      alt="Bana cabel cars"
    >
  </a>
  <figcaption>
    <p>Bana cabel cars</p>
  </figcaption>
</figure>
Overall, 2024 thăng trầm cũng nhiều nhưng cũng nhờ vậy tui đã chính chắn hơn và cũng đã tìm được mục tiêu trong cuộc sống. Để tổng kết lại năm vừa rồi thì post này sẽ như một cái archive lưu trữ những sự kiện chính trong năm.
<h4 id="142-192-hội-dn-dn-gặp-mặt-lần-đầu"><em>14/2-19/2: Hội DN-DN gặp mặt lần đầu.</em></h4>
<figure>
  <a href="https://minhvu1512.github.io/images/2024_recap/Beachshoes.JPG">
    <img 
      src="/images/2024_recap/Beachshoes.JPG" 
      alt="Beachshoes"
    >
  </a>
  <figcaption>
    <p>Random pic of our shoes at Mỹ Khê beach</p>
  </figcaption>
</figure>
The group is entitled DN-DN because 2 out of the 6 of us live in Đà Nẵng, and the rest is in Đồng Nai. We became friends on a whim through playing video games online. I was introduced to the group by a girl I befriended in math class. Before moving to Đà Nẵng with her family, she was born and raised in Đồng Nai. Initially, I only expected the group to be acquaintances since everything started out so randomly, but through consistent online conversations, we became close-knit. Before the 1-week trip in Feb, our friendship had already spanned through 3 years of high school, so they were the people whom I adored the most. We met each other in Đà Nẵng, so the people who were living in Đồng Nai, or what we usually call: "The Đồng Nai headquarters," had to fly to Đà Nẵng. They were a pair of siblings who are twins, a high achiever whose hobby is creating tiktok edits of movies, and a quick-witted queer who's straightforward and would usually spit out the most unhinged yet comical things I would've never thought about. The schedule for our "little rendezvous" was planned out thoroughly, accommodating every desire of each person in the group. For me, it was a week of moving back and forth from my house to the place that the group was staying in. My mom actually didn't allow me to have a sleepover with them, thinking that I wouldn't catch any shut-eye for a whole week. It was a bit irritating because I needed to spend more time and money commuting in the morning to stay aligned with our plans. On the bright side, at least I got to spend a week hanging out with them. It's one of those memories that I always think about regularly. Even though some things didn't go as planned, overall, we had a great week. We also celebrated a late birthday for that high achiever guy I mentioned. Some videos will be included with this post.
<h4 id="217-nhận-được-job-offer-làm-trợ-giảng-cho-mads-cộng-thêm-2110-và-2012-nhận-điểm-thi-sat"><em>21/7: Nhận được job offer làm trợ giảng cho MADS (cộng thêm 21/10 và 20/12 nhận điểm thi SAT).</em></h4>
<figure>
  <a href="https://minhvu1512.github.io/images/2024_recap/MADS.jpg">
    <img 
      src="/images/2024_recap/MADS.jpg" 
      alt="MADS"
    >
  </a>
  <figcaption>
    <p>MADS webpage</p>
  </figcaption>
</figure>
Hoàn toàn không expect là sẽ được mời vào làm trợ giảng ấy nhưng cũng cảm ơn nhiều vì trung tâm đã tin tưởng và tạo cơ hội để tui phát triển bản thân. Ban đầu tính tháng 3 sẽ thi lại SAT vì không thích con điểm cũ của mình lắm ấy nhưng vì bận vài thứ nên bản thân cũng không có động lực lắm. Đến khi vào làm thì mới mới quyết tâm cải thiện điểm để xứng với danh làm trợ giảng. Thi lại được 1550 thấy điểm cũm cao nhưng mà mình lại muốn điểm cao hơn nữa lol. Không biết tháng 3 sắp tới có nên thi tiếp nữa không. Kiểu tui tin là điểm số phải tồn tại song song với kĩ năng để chứng mình một người có dạy tốt hay không. Tuy tui cũng đang cố cải thiện giọng nói với cách diễn đạt của mình để trở nên tốt hơn nhưng tui vẫn hơi tự ti về điểm của mình sao ấy. 
<p>Ngoài ra thì nhờ có công việc này thì tui mới trở nên goal oriented hơn một xíu. Việc giảng dạy cũng nằm trong định hướng ban đầu của tui ấy nhưng tui không có prioritize nó lên đầu. Bây giờ tui cũng hoàn toàn xác định được bản thân muốn làm gì để có thể hạnh phúc rồi. Cộng thêm kinh nghiệm đang tích lũy dần khi vừa dạy cho trung tâm với vừa dạy riêng nữa nên tui mới stick with việc giảng dạy. Chỉ sợ mình đang cạn dần thời gian để có thể học hỏi.</p>
<h4 id="109-bắt-đầu-ghé-qua-office-hours-của-prof"><em>10/9: Bắt đầu ghé qua office hours của prof.</em></h4>
<figure>
  <a href="https://minhvu1512.github.io/images/2024_recap/noodles.JPEG">
    <img 
      src="/images/2024_recap/noodles.JPEG" 
      alt="Noodles at Chin"
    >
  </a>
  <figcaption>
    <p>Noodles at Chin on my birthday</p>
  </figcaption>
</figure>
Hình như tui brag về prof của tui hoài nhưng he actually deserves to be in my top 3 fav person of the year. Tui vẫn nhớ rõ ngày đầu tiên qua gặp ổng. Tui lúc đấy confess rằng bản thân sẽ đổi ngành. Tui nói vui vui thôi chứ cũng không có nghiêm túc lắm nhưng ổng cũng rất quan tâm và kêu rằng tui cứ thoải mái qua office hours của ổng để có spiritual guidance. Từ đấy mỗi tuần thứ 3 và thứ 5 2h đến 4h tui đều dành thời gian để ghé qua văn phòng của ông prof. Course material không có bị khó lắm nên mỗi lúc qua tui chỉ cần hỏi có 1-2 câu nhỏ thôi à. Ổng rep lại 1 câu cũng đủ để tui hiểu bài rồi lol. Ngoài ra thì tui cũng giúp ổng assist cho mấy sinh viên khác nếu lúc đó office đông quá. Qua học kì sắp tới tui sẽ làm unofficial TA của ổng. Ổng định trả tui 6 đồng 1 giờ. Nhìn hơi underpaid vậy thôi chứ thật ra đang cho tui free tiền ấy. Nhưng mà tui không dám nhận tiền lắm vì lí do tui hỏi có muốn tui làm TA không là vì tui muốn ghé qua văn phòng của ổng á. Cuộc sống bên này hơi cô đơn chút. Ổng là người bạn duy nhất của tui ở đây á nên tui mới quý ổng đến vậy. Trước tui khóc vì bị overwhelmed ổng còn động viên nữa lol. Sinh nhật tui ổng còn dẫn đi ăn. Anw, tldr; best prof I've ever had, life changing connection.
<h4 id="here-are-some-honerable-mentions"><em>Here are some honerable mentions:</em></h4>
<p>20/3: Bắt đầu nhận dạy tiếng anh giao tiếp và được 3 anh chị học cùng 4 tháng.</p>
<p>10/10: Tâm sự với HMĐK và Nlinh</p>
<p>12/10: Call với hội cấp 3 và Bchau kể về cuộc sống bên này và dự định tương lai.</p>
<p>15/12: Sinh nhật</p>
<p>Rất rất nhiều cuộc trò chuyện của tui với bạn bè nhưng tui không nhớ rõ ngày</p>
<p>List những người tui biết ơn vì đã giúp đỡ tui rất nhiều trong năm vừa rồi: BN, LVBC, TT, NL, Shane Donahue.</p>
<p>List album nhạc hay năm vừa rồi tôi hay nghe: Brat, The Idler Wheel&hellip;, When the Pawn&hellip;, Pure Heroine, Titanic Rising, The Rise and Fall of a Midwest Princess, Charm, Daddy&rsquo;s Home, Masseduction.</p>
<p>New year&rsquo;s resolution: Học giỏi hơn, phát triển nhiều hơn.</p>
<p>Cảm ơn vì đã đọc đến đoạn này ❤</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
